lme.co.uk 2016-12-05

# London Metal Exchange: Privacy statement

## Information about our organisation and website 

Our privacy policy covers The London Metal Exchange (“LME”), LME Clear Limited (“LMEC”) and their websites http://www.lme.com/, <https://secure.lme.com/> and <http://www.lmelive.com/>. It also covers any email communications that we may send to you or your company. The LME is based in the United Kingdom. The LME is a recognised investment exchange under the Financial Services and Markets Act 2000, recognised and supervised by the FCA. 

We are committed to protecting your privacy. This online privacy policy describes the ways in which we collect information from you and what we may use it for. Please read the policy to check how your information will be treated. This policy may be amended from time to time so please check it regularly. 

The terms of this statement should be read together with our website terms and conditions, any additional terms and conditions, disclaimers or other contractual terms you have entered into with us and any applicable mandatory laws and regulations. 

## Accessing our site anonymously 

You can access our websites and browse some parts of our websites without disclosing information that identifies you personally. Other parts of our websites require you to provide information that identifies you personally in order for you to access restricted content. 

When accessing our websites anonymously we will use cookies to identify your browser, but this information is not personally identifiable. Please see our Cookies Policy for further information on the LME’s use of cookies. 

## The data we collect 

We may collect data from you in a number of ways. During the course of your visits to our websites data may be collected in the following ways: 

  1. Data you submit on the website via forms such as registration and profile updates; 
  2. information on the pages you request; such as time of visit, content requested, IP number and other information your browser software sends to our web servers when such requests are made; and 
  3. through the use of cookies to identify you, your browser, browsing preferences and whether you visited us from content or advertisements we place on other websites or emails. 

When we send or receive email from you: 

  1. The address and content of the emails concerned; 
  2. the success or failure of our attempts to send you email; and 
  3. when you receive, open or click on content in emails we send you and any subsequent visits you or other recipients make to our websites. 

When you call us: 

  1. the telephone number you are calling from, time, date and the content of the call; and 
  2. we may also record the telephone conversation in compliance with our telephone recording policy. 

We may combine the information we have collected from you with information from other sources, such as public records or bodies, or private organisations. 

## Our use of your data 

We will use the data we collect to provide you with the information or services you have requested and for internal customer administration and business purposes. 

If you consent to receive marketing materials from us, we may use your data to send you marketing and other materials relating to the LME or another company in the Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited group. 

If you are not registered to receive marketing information and wish to receive such information, please register with us. You may withdraw your consent to us sending you marketing materials at any time by sending an email to: [info@lme.com](mailto:info@lme.com). 

## Confidentiality / Security 

We use a secure transmission method to enable you to send us the following types of personal data: 

  * primary personal data (such as name and contact details); and 
  * identifiers (such as credit card details, website login username and password). 

We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to seek to protect the personal data that we have under our control from: 

  * unauthorised access; 
  * improper use or disclosure; 
  * unauthorised modification; and 
  * unlawful destruction or accidental loss. 

All our employees and data processors who have access to and are associated with the processing of personal data are obliged to respect the confidentiality of your personal data. 

Under certain circumstances we may provide your details to organisations who work on our behalf. We will make sure that the supplier has appropriate security measures in place and will contractually require them to comply with this privacy policy. 

Except where you have explicitly given us permission, we will not pass your details onto any other organisations (except as noted above) or publish them publically. Where you have requested us to pass on details to related organisations we will require them to comply with this privacy policy. 

## Consent 

By continuing to use this website and by providing any personal data to us via this website or email addresses and phone numbers provided on this website, you are consenting to our use of your personal data as set out in this privacy policy. Please do not send us any personal data if you do not want that information to be used by us in any manner. 

## Access to the personal data we may hold about you 

You have the right to apply for a copy of the data we hold about you and to have any inaccurate data about you corrected. For more information, please contact us using the details below.   

## Privacy support

If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policy, please contact: 

By post: 10 Finsbury Square, London, EC2A 1AJ  
Phone: +44 (0) 207 113 8888  
Fax: +44 (0) 207 264 5541  
Email address: [info@lme.com  
](mailto:info@lme.com?subject=Privacy%20policy)or via our Contact form
